Jarrod Sport

MEDIA PRODUCER



Name	Jarrod Sport
D.O.B	28 April 9, 1986
Web	jarrod-sport.flavors.me
Contact	650.267.9617
Email	√ jarrodsport@gmail.com

EDUCATION

University	University of California, Santa Cruz
Degree	Legal Studies and Social Documentation
Training	Audio, video, and photography production



EXPERIENCE

World Affairs Council

Sep 2013 - present

Media Producer

Responsible for producing all forms of media content for online marketing and distribution, including event live streams, speaker interviews, photography exhibitions, podcasts, and other institutionally relevant media campaigns; Utilize HD video and DSLR photography equipment to capture media, and edit on a Mac platform utilizing Final Cut Pro 7 and X, the Adobe Creative Suite 5.5 (notably, Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, and Audition); Interface and collaborate with every constituent of the organization to design and execute media campaigns; Manage the YouTube Channel.

KTVU Channel 2 News

May 2012 - present

Video Editor

Edit video and multimedia content for the early morning weekend news programming; Manage constant deadlines and time constraints to edit media from multiple news sources, including local and national outlets, to ensure that the dozens of short news stories make it to live air without error; Coordinate with on-site directors, reporters, producers, and writers to produce a fast-paced, complex show to reach 30,000+ viewers.

FORA.tv

May 2011 – Sep 2013

Manager of Media Post-Production

Led the Post-Production team of five editors and two copywriters in the site's video and content production; Edited company marketing videos, promos, and event sizzle reels, including the design and integration of motion graphics and digital assets; Quality assured lives stream video productions; Interfaced with senior management, production staff, and clients to produce and post video content online according to the contract; Managed data and storage systems, and maintained network and servers; Coordinated media transfer and maintained company CMS; Curated metadata, optimized site tagging and SEO, and produced and approved editorial copy; Syndicated partner and original content on YouTube, Hulu, and other digital media channels.



PROFILE



in http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jarrod-sport/11/bb2/42a

Hello! I'm Jarrod, a 28 year old media producer based in San Francisco, California.

A native of the San Francisco Bay Area, I've been graced to learn and produce in one of the world's largest intersections of new media storytelling and social change. The social and political movements that affect all of us are fueled by people with compelling, vibrant stories, and it's my mission to document their experiences. Every story has its own identity, so I have utilized several mediums - including audio, video, and photography - to capture the sights and sounds of a rich narrative.



SKILLS



Specialities

Video production Media post-production Event live streaming Media management



Computer

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Adobe After Effects Final Cut Pro 7 and X



Knowledge

Narrative storytelling Story development Ethical theory Lighting Sound production Motion graphics Content distribution



Hobbies

Movies Music Documentary Photography Mentorship Reading Creative writing